<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source and Community contributions on Swapnil Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source and Community contributions on Swapnil Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redocly - Google Season of Docs</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/redoclyoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/redoclyoss/</guid>
      <description>Summary When Google announced the Season of Docs 2021, I led Redocly&amp;rsquo;s effort on submitting a proposal for our open source projects, Redoc and OpenAPI cli. The proposal was accepted by Google, and we hired two technical writers to work on our products.
I managed the administrative part of the project on behalf of Redocly, and also assisted and mentored technical writers contributing to our open source documentation.
Our project had a successful outcome which I captured in our case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write the Docs Australia</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/wtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 12:25:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/wtd/</guid>
      <description>Context Write the Docs is a global community of people who care about documentation. We consider everyone who cares about communication, documentation, and their users to be a member of our community. This can be programmers, tech writers, developer advocates, customer support, marketers, and anyone else who wants people to have great experiences with software.
Contribution While we have had other communities in Australia that covered technical documentation sporadically, there was no community for like minded people to get together and talk about documentation issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geonetwork</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/geonetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 23:14:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/geonetwork/</guid>
      <description>Proposal My proposal for the GeoNetwork project involved providing an experienced Technical Writer&amp;rsquo;s perspective to help amplify the quality and effectiveness of some of the existing writing initiatives within the GeoNetwork project, one of the projects under the umbrella of the Open Source Geospatial Foundation (OSGeo).
Project scope  Review GeoNetwork docs, using existing analysis provided by team: https://wiki.osgeo.org/wiki/Season_of_Docs_Ideas_2019#GeoNetwork Create best-practice templates that writing volunteers can use as a basis for creating new or standardising existing content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubeflow</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/kubeflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:33:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/kubeflow/</guid>
      <description>Context Google Kubeflow team organised a Kubeflow doc sprint in July 2019. A doc sprint is like a hackathon for docs. Over the course of three days, participants developed tutorials and fixed documentation bugs.
Participation I participated on Day 2 and helped document an overview topic on using Jupyter notebooks in Kubeflow.
Links Github PR: https://github.com/kubeflow/website/pull/914</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
