<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docs on Swapnil Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/tags/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docs on Swapnil Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swapnilogale.github.io/tags/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redocly - Google Season of Docs</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/redoclyoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/redoclyoss/</guid>
      <description>Summary When Google announced the Season of Docs 2021, I led Redocly&amp;rsquo;s effort on submitting a proposal for our open source projects, Redoc and OpenAPI cli. The proposal was accepted by Google, and we hired two technical writers to work on our products.
I managed the administrative part of the project on behalf of Redocly, and also assisted and mentored technical writers contributing to our open source documentation.
Our project had a successful outcome which I captured in our case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Review</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/reviewpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/reviewpost/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by KnowledgeOwl to write a guest post for their blog.
I wrote about why proper reviews are vital to the documentation process, how to plan for them, various kinds of reviews, and how to provide to feedback (if you are the one reviewing someone else&amp;rsquo;s docs!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How API docs became my silver lining</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apipost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apipost/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by KnowledgeOwl to write a guest post for their blog.
I wrote about my experiences with starting with API documentation, growing my skills in this area and how API documentation offers an exciting and challenging space for technical writers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geonetwork</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/geonetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 23:14:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/geonetwork/</guid>
      <description>Proposal My proposal for the GeoNetwork project involved providing an experienced Technical Writer&amp;rsquo;s perspective to help amplify the quality and effectiveness of some of the existing writing initiatives within the GeoNetwork project, one of the projects under the umbrella of the Open Source Geospatial Foundation (OSGeo).
Project scope  Review GeoNetwork docs, using existing analysis provided by team: https://wiki.osgeo.org/wiki/Season_of_Docs_Ideas_2019#GeoNetwork Create best-practice templates that writing volunteers can use as a basis for creating new or standardising existing content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubeflow</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/kubeflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:33:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/kubeflow/</guid>
      <description>Context Google Kubeflow team organised a Kubeflow doc sprint in July 2019. A doc sprint is like a hackathon for docs. Over the course of three days, participants developed tutorials and fixed documentation bugs.
Participation I participated on Day 2 and helped document an overview topic on using Jupyter notebooks in Kubeflow.
Links Github PR: https://github.com/kubeflow/website/pull/914</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
