<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentation Projects on Swapnil Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentation Projects on Swapnil Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 21:57:42 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Product marketing blogs</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/productblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 21:57:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/productblogs/</guid>
      <description>Context Providing Redocly customers with a monthly update on new features been rolled out across its products.
Problem When I started at Redocly, a lot of customers were sometimes unaware of various features been rolled out across our products. The only way they could find this out was by contacting technical support.
It was essential to let customers know frequently what we were working on and how it would enhance their developer experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product documentation, Information architecture, Content strategy</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/productdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 21:57:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/productdocs/</guid>
      <description>Context As Redocly&amp;rsquo;s first Technical Writer Advocate, the goal of this role is to help the community of technical writers by advocating for a docs-like-code approach and offering them the skills and know-how for how to make it happen.
Problem Redocly makes API design and documentation software with the goal to improve the writer and developer experience.
As part of this goal, they required a Technical Writer Advocate to not only assist with writing technical content, but also needed someone to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Portals</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/apidocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 21:57:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/apidocs/</guid>
      <description>Context SEEK was refreshing its API integration products for partners and hirers.
Problem The various SEEK teams were working on building and delivering a single API built using GraphQL, OAuth 2.0 and optional webhooks. The Partner Integration team was working on refreshing the onboarding experience for partners and hirers, to improve process efficiencies and streamline the self-serving nature of the process.
As part of this project, they required a Technical Writer to assist with redesigning the onboarding portal and review the developer portal content for consistency and accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDK documentation</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/sdkdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 21:57:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/sdkdocs/</guid>
      <description>Context Zip simplifies how you pay everywhere and save every day by offering fast, fair and seamless payment solutions online and in-store.
Problem I was contacted by one of the Zip development teams to assist with editing and creating content for their Zip SDK developer documentation hub.
Contribution I collaborated with the Zip team to review their existing SDK documentation for iOS and Android devices, and make recommendations on style, voice and tone, to make it clearer to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical specifications and API documentation</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/techspecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 22:33:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/techspecs/</guid>
      <description>Context The role of Australian Energy Market Operator (AEMO) is to manage the electricity and gas systems and markets across Australia, helping to ensure Australians have access to affordable, secure and reliable energy.
I was part of AEMO&amp;rsquo;s distributed energy initiatives and a market trial project, working with multiple teams to document a range of content for different audiences.
Opportunity I was assigned to manage the entire suite of documentation, for two Australia-wide distributed energy initiatives documenting technical specifications, API design, user guides, and reference documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Help</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/onlinehelp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 21:57:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/onlinehelp/</guid>
      <description>Context Planifi helps lean organisations do more with less: increase productivity, decrease wasted resource hours, and deliver visibility into project performance across your entire firm.
Problem A niche startup, Planifi develops and delivers a suite of products to architecture and engineering firms to manage their projects, schedules, resources and forecasting. While they were developing their product, they needed a Technical Writer to create end user documentation that could be used by Training and Support teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process documentation and work instructions</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/processdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 23:47:07 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/creations/processdocs/</guid>
      <description>Context NBN Co was established in 2009 to design, build and operate Australia’s wholesale broadband access network.
I was part of NBN&amp;rsquo;s Hybrid Fibre Coaxial (HFC) Network Operations team, working with process analysts to support a large capability project across various Network teams.
Opportunity I was asked to unofficially lead a team of technical writers working on a large documentation project creating process docs and work instructions. When we started as a group, there were no existing documents or knowledge to support process maps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
