<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentations and Publications on Swapnil Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentations and Publications on Swapnil Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The secret sauce behind successful APIs</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apidays/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I spoke about the secret sauce behind successful APIs - documentation. This talk covered:
 Problem areas with API projects from experience, An API&amp;rsquo;s journey from a producer as well as the consumer perspectives, and How to use documentation along each step of the API lifecycle.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Writer Advocacy and Managing Write the Docs Australia</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techcommpodcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techcommpodcast/</guid>
      <description>I chatted with the host of The Not Boring Tech Writer about:
 The Write the Docs Australia community Organising meetups and conference for the Write the Docs Australia community Why it is necessary to advocate for good documentation practices What my role as a Technical Writer Advocate is all about  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the tech in technical writer</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techwriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techwriter/</guid>
      <description>I take the audience through a few ideas and examples (both personal and community sourced) for:
 Looking under the hood (of WYSIWYG tools), Learning just enough Git, Thinking in plain text, Templates, toolchain and processes, and Automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making content sustainable</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/makedocssustainable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/makedocssustainable/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I question how to make our content sustainable, especially now when our content is growing at an unprecedented rate. Just when we thought we had a handle on user needs, that seems to be changing every minute. What does it really mean to create sustainable content and how do we achieve this?
 Docs and processes are a mess, but they don’t have to be. Reuse. Reduce. Recycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the deal with Release notes?</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/releasenotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/releasenotes/</guid>
      <description>Product managers swear by them, development managers are keen on producing them and quite so often your developers or engineers will help (grudgingly) craft them.
Release notes are everywhere, be it a product or a process. They are quite often your first point of communication with customers eager to know what’s new or fixed in your product or process. In some instances, they also become the most frequently or commonly accessed content on your documentation site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When bad screenshots happen to good writers</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/screenshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/screenshots/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You have your content moving at a swift pace, your documents are getting reviewed in a timely fashion (surprise!) and you are nicely heading towards your release milestone.
The only thing missing are some key screenshots that you need to put in before you publish your documentation. What you get instead are some hideous images posing as screenshots, that were captured randomly, bears no resemblance to your instructions and would make no sense whatsoever to the end user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Review</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/reviewpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/reviewpost/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by KnowledgeOwl to write a guest post for their blog.
I wrote about why proper reviews are vital to the documentation process, how to plan for them, various kinds of reviews, and how to provide to feedback (if you are the one reviewing someone else&amp;rsquo;s docs!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How API docs became my silver lining</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apipost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/apipost/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by KnowledgeOwl to write a guest post for their blog.
I wrote about my experiences with starting with API documentation, growing my skills in this area and how API documentation offers an exciting and challenging space for technical writers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write the Docs Podcast</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/wtdpodcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/wtdpodcast/</guid>
      <description>I chatted with the Write the Docs podcast team about:
 The Write the Docs Australian conference more wind-downs and ramp-ups, Highlights from the just-finished WTD Prague conference, Speakers announced for upcoming Write the Docs Australia conference, The Good Docs Project, The tech writing scene in Australia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justifying the use of Single Sourcing</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/madcapflare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/madcapflare/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by Madcap Software to write a guest post for their blog. I wrote about a case study where I had to justify the use of single sourcing at the organisation I was working at the time.
To summarise how the single sourcing strategy worked at the organisation was:
 Avoided issues with duplication of content. All my content resided in one location, reducing inconsistencies. Set a consistent look and feel across all the documentation projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
